stjude.org 2017-01-30

# U.S. Privacy Policy Statement - St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital

This privacy statement applies to St. Jude Children's Research Hospital and its fundraising organization, American Lebanese Syrian Associated Charities (ALSAC). St. Jude and ALSAC respect the privacy of our visitors and donors.

For information regarding our privacy policies for Canadian residents, please view our Canadian privacy policy.

This site collects information such as the visitor's domain name, site traffic patterns and server usage statistics. This information is used to improve the performance and content of our Web pages and to personalize content and layout of our pages for individual visitors.

We do not collect and store your email address unless you choose to communicate with us in one of several ways:

  * You contact us directly via email.
  * You provide your email address to us via phone, mail, electronic form or paper sign-up sheet.
  * You opt out of future messaging after receiving a "Forward to a Friend" or "Share With Your Network" email message.

We do not sell or rent our email lists to third-party organizations. We do share this information with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf, but we do not authorize these service providers to use or disclose the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements.

Third-party personally identifiable information you provide for memorial or honor donations or for merchandise shipping will not be shared.

We may occasionally conduct voluntary surveys on this site. Personally identifiable information collected in these surveys will not be shared. Aggregate results may be shared for analysis by third parties. The aggregate data cannot be used to identify individuals.

We may ask you to provide information in a few circumstances. When you donate, register or purchase items from stjude.org, we will need personal information, such as name, address, telephone number, email address, and credit card number, so that we can process your donation or order, notify you of order status or provide a receipt.

We do not rent or sell customer information to outside marketers. We might use the information you provide to share information about services or products you have requested or to inform you of promotional offers that might be of interest.

We use shipping companies to ship merchandise and a credit card processor for merchandise orders and donations. These companies do not share or use personally identifiable information for secondary purposes.

We use cookies to store visitors' preferences, alert visitors to new areas of the site, customize Web page content based on visitor interests and record past activity in order to provide better service. Cookies are small text files that do not damage a visitor's system or files. Most browsers will allow a user to accept or deny cookies. If a visitor rejects our cookies, they may still use our site.

St. Jude, or those acting on our behalf, uses web beacons to access St. Jude cookies inside and outside our network of websites. Web pages may contain an electronic file called a web beacon that allows a web site to count users who have visited specific content or sites or to access certain cookies. Cookies allow St. Jude to personalize your experience when you visit St. Jude web sites and those that may precede or follow the stjude.org domain.  This file and technology enables us to target relevant content or information to enhance your user experience. Most browsers will allow a user to accept or deny cookies. If a visitor rejects our cookies, they may still use our site.

Our server uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption to protect credit card and other information submitted via the forms on this site. SSL is the industry standard security protocol. All off-line information is securely stored and is accessible only by authorized staff.

This site contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of sites not owned by St. Jude Children's Research Hospital or ALSAC. We encourage our visitors to be aware of when they leave our site and to read the privacy statement of any site that collects personally identifiable data.

Any changes to our privacy policy will be posted on all sites owned by St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital or ALSAC.

St. Jude Children's Research Hospital will discontinue contact with any person upon oral or written request. Write: St. Jude Children's Research Hospital, Attn: Donor Services, 501 St. Jude Place, Memphis, TN 38105. Or phone 1-800-822-6344, or email [donors@stjude.org](mailto:donors@stjude.org).

The quickest means of unsubscribing from electronic communications is through the [Email Management Center](https://apps.stjude.org/sjemc/jsp/EMCLogin.jsp) or by using the unsubscribe function on the eNewsletter you are receiving.

If you have any questions about St. Jude Children's Research Hospital, ALSAC, or our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us at:

**St. Jude Children’s Research Hospital**  
Communications  
262 Danny Thomas Place  
Memphis, TN 38105-3678  
(901) 595-3306
